[Applause]
[掌声]
in the evening or good morning I do not know what time it is there at any time I am though
在傍晚或早上好，我不知道现在什么时候和你在一起
happy to attend your meeting I really liked the title
很高兴参加您的会议，我真的很喜欢这个标题
the feature because while looking to the future in a comfortable life today to dialogue
该功能是因为在展望今天舒适生活中的未来时进行对话
looking to the future invites you to contact a trustee
展望未来，邀请您联系受托人
the future is made of you, that is, it is made up of encounters because life flows
未来是由你创造的，也就是说，它是由相遇构成的，因为生命在流动
through relationships several years of life have made me mature more and more
通过关系，几年的生活使我越来越成熟
the conviction that the existence of each of us is linked to that of
相信我们每个人的存在都与我们的存在息息相关的信念
others life is not a passing time
别人的生活不是流逝的时光
but time to meet
但是有时间见面
meeting by listening to sick suffering migrants they face
通过听取他们所面对的患病苦难移民来开会
tremendous difficulties in search of a better future leading prisoners
寻找更好的未来主要囚犯的巨大困难
hell in their hearts especially young people who don't have
地狱在他们的心中，尤其是那些没有的年轻人
work often accompanies me a question why them that not me
工作经常伴随着我一个问题，为什么他们不是我
I too was born into a migrant family my dad
我父亲也出生在一个移民家庭
my grandparents like many other italians left for argentina and have
我的祖父母像许多其他意大利人一样，去了阿根廷，
known the fate of those who are left with nothing
知道那些一无所有的人的命运
I too could have been among the discarded of today therefore in my heart
我也可能是今天被抛弃的人之一
it always remains the same because I would like them and not me
它总是保持不变，因为我想要他们而不是我
first of all that this meeting helps us to remember that we all have
首先，这次会议有助于我们记住我们都有
each other's need that none of us are an island an autonomous self and
彼此的需求是我们每个人都不是一个孤岛，一个自治的自我，
independent from others that we can build the future only together without
与他人独立，我们只有在一起才能建立未来
exclude anyone we often do not think about it but in reality
排除我们通常不考虑的任何人，但实际上
everything is connected and we need to heal our connections too
一切都已连接，我们也需要修复连接
that harsh judgment that I carry in my heart against my brother and that sister
我对兄弟和那个姐姐心里刻薄的判断
untreated wound that evil not forgiven that rancor that will only make me
未经治疗的伤口，邪恶，无法原谅，那只会让我生气的怨恨
evil and a bit of war that I carry inside and an outbreak in the heart from
我内心深处的邪恶和战争，以及内心的爆发
extinguish lest it ignite in a fire that does not leave many genus today
熄灭，以免在今天没有留下很多属的火中点燃
for various reasons they seem not to believe that a happy future is possible
由于各种原因，他们似乎不相信幸福的未来是可能的
these fears must be taken seriously but they are not invincible and can be overcome
这些恐惧必须得到认真对待，但它们并非立于不败之地，可以克服。
if not what we also close in on ourselves because happiness is experienced
如果不是，我们也会自我封闭，因为经历了幸福
only as a gift of harmony of every detail with everything, even the sciences
只是作为每个细节与万物和谐相处的礼物，甚至是科学
you know it better than I show us today an understanding of reality where every
您比我今天向我们展示的对现实的了解更好，
what exists in connection in continuous interaction with the
与持续互动中存在的联系
others and here I come to my second message how nice it would be if the
其他人，在这里，我来谈我的第二条消息，如果
growth of scientific and technological innovations also matched one
科技创新的增长也与之匹敌
more and more equity and social inclusion how nice it would be if while
越来越多的平等和社会包容
we discover new distant planets we rediscover the needs of our brother e
我们发现了遥远的新星球，重新发现了我们兄弟的需求，
of the sister who orbit around me how nice that fraternity would be
在我周围旋转的姐姐的那份兄弟情谊会多么美好
this word so beautiful sometimes scoma would not reduce us alone
这个词如此美丽，有时斯卡玛不会让我们一个人失望
social assistance but became a basic attitude in the choices a
社会援助，但成为选择的基本态度
political economic scientific level in the relations between people among peoples
人与人之间关系中的政治经济学科学水平
and countries only education in fraternity in concrete solidarity
和国家/地区，只有在团结互助下进行博爱教育
it can overcome the throwaway culture that is not just about food and goods but
它可以克服不仅仅涉及食物和商品的一次性文化，而且可以克服
first of all people who are marginalized by techno and economic systems
首先是被技术和经济系统边缘化的人
where at the center, without realizing it, there is often no longer the man but the products
在中心位置，没有意识到这一点，通常不再是人，而是产品
of man
男人的
solidarity is a word that many want to remove from the dictionary
团结是一个很多人想从字典中删除的单词
solidarity however is not an automatic mechanism it cannot be programmed either
团结不是自动机制，也无法编程
commander and a free response that comes from
指挥官和来自的免费回应
heart of each yes a free answer if 1 understands
每个人的心是一个免费的答案，如果1理解
that his life even in the midst of so many contradictions and a gift that love is
他的一生即使在如此多的矛盾和礼物中也是如此，爱是
the source and meaning of life as it will draw hold back desire
生命的来源和意义，因为它会抑制对生命的渴望
doing good to others to be active in good requires memory
对他人做好事以保持积极主动需要记忆
it takes courage and also creativity
需要勇气和创造力
they told me that you sort out a lot of very creative people
他们告诉我，你选出了很多很有创造力的人
yes love and asking for an ingenious concrete creative answer are not enough
是的，爱并要求一个独具匠心的具体创造性答案是不够的
the good intentions and the ritual formulas that he breaks that often only serve a
他打破的好意和礼节通常只会起到
calm conscience together let us help remember that others do not
让我们保持冷静的良心，让我们帮助您记住别人没有
they are statistics or numbers the other has a face
它们是统计数据或数字，对方有一张脸
the tool is always a concrete face, a brother to take care of
工具永远是混凝土的脸，兄弟要照顾
there is a story that jesus told to make people understand the difference between
耶稣讲了一个故事，让人们了解两者之间的区别
who does not bother and who takes care of the other
谁不打扰谁照顾别人
you have probably heard of it is the parable of the good Samaritan when
您可能听说过，这是好撒玛利亚人的寓言，
they asked jesus who my neighbor is, that is, who should i take care of
他们问耶稣我的邻居是谁，也就是我应该照顾谁
Jesus told this story the story of a man the thieves had
耶稣讲了这个故事，一个小偷有一个男人的故事
assaulted by stolen abandoned path along the road two people
沿着这条路被偷走的废弃小路袭击了两个人
very respectable of the time a priest a Levite saw him but
利未人的祭司见他的时候非常可敬。
they passed by without stopping then came a Samaritan who belonged to
他们路过不停，然后来了一个撒玛利亚人，他属于
a despised ethnic group and this Samaritan at the sight of that man
一个被人鄙视的民族和这个撒玛利亚人
wounded on the ground did not pass over like the others as if
受伤的人没有像其他人那样越过
nothing had happened but he had compassion for it he was moved and
什么都没发生，但他有同情心，他被感动了，
this compassion leads him to make very concrete gestures towards oil
这种同情心使他对石油做出了非常具体的姿态
and wine on that man's wounds brought him a tree and paid out of his own pocket for
那个男人伤口上的酒给他带来了一棵树，从他自己的口袋里掏出
his assistance the story of the good Samaritan and the history of humanity of
他的协助下，撒玛利亚人的故事和人类的历史
today on the path of peoples there are wounds caused by the fact that at the center
今天，在人民的道路上，伤口是由以下事实造成的：
there is money there is things not people
有钱就没有人
and there is often the habit of those who believe themselves to be good not to care about
那些相信自己是对的而不关心的人经常会养成习惯
others leaving so many human beings whole peoples back to earth for the
其他人让那么多人类整个民族回到地球
Street
街道
however, there are also those who give life to a new world
但是，也有一些人为新世界赋予生命
taking care of others even at their own expense, in fact, mother said
妈妈说，即使自费也要照顾别人
Teresa of Calcutta cannot be loved except at one's own expense
加尔各答的特蕾莎修女（Teresa）不能自拔，除非自费
we have a lot to do and we must do it together
我们有很多事情要做，我们必须一起做
but how to deal with the evil we breathe
但是如何应对我们呼吸的邪恶
thank god no system can undo the opening to the good
谢天谢地，没有系统可以撤销对美好事物的开放
compassion and the ability to react to evil that arise from the heart of man
人心所产生的同情心和对邪恶做出反应的能力
now you will tell me they are beautiful words but I am not even a Samaritan
现在你会告诉我他们是美丽的话，但我什至不是撒玛利亚人
mother teresa of calcutta instead each of us is precious each of us and
加尔各答的特蕾莎修女，而不是我们每个人都是珍贵的我们每个人，
irreplaceable in the eyes of God in the night of the conflicts that we are
在我们所面对的冲突之夜，在上帝眼中是不可替代的
crossing each of us can be a candle
穿越我们每个人都可以像一支蜡烛
lit that reminds that light prevails over darkness not the other way around
提醒人们，光胜于黑暗，而不是反过来
for us Christians the future has a name that this name hope has hope
对我们基督徒来说，未来有一个名字，这个名字希望有希望
it does not mean being naive optimists who ignore the drama of evil and
这并不意味着成为天真的乐观主义者，而忽略了邪恶和邪恶的戏剧。
of humanity the hope and virtue of a heart that does not close in the dark does not
人类的希望和美德不会在黑暗中关闭
he stops at the past he does not vivacchia in the present but he knows how to see tomorrow there
他停在过去，他现在不活泼，但他知道如何去那里看明天
hope and the open door on coming hope is a seed of humble life
希望和即将到来的希望敞开的门是卑微生活的种子
hidden which, however, over time turns into a large tree and like a yeast
隐藏，但是随着时间的流逝，它变成一棵大树，就像酵母一样
invisible that makes all the pasta grow that gives flavor to all life e
使所有面食都长出来的无形食品，为所有生活增添风味
it can do so much because a single small light is enough to feed on hope
它可以做很多事情，因为一个小小的光就足以养活希望
and the darkness will no longer be complete, only one man is enough for there to be
黑暗不再完整，只有一个人足以满足
hope and that man can be you then there is another tool is another tool e
希望，那个男人可以成为你，那么还有另一种工具是另一种工具
then we become us and when there is us, hope begins, not that
然后我们成为我们，当我们存在时，希望就开始了，不是那样
started with you when there is a revolution in us begins the third e
当我们发生革命时，从您开始
The last message I would like to share today is about the revolution there
我今天要分享的最后一条信息是关于那里的革命
revolution of tenderness what is tenderness and love that comes close
温柔的革命是什么？
and concrete is a movement that starts from the heart reaches the eyes to the ears
具体是从心脏到眼睛再到耳朵的运动
to the hands tenderness and use the eyes to
用手压痛并用眼睛
see the other use the ears to hear the other to hear the cry
看见对方用耳朵听对方听到声音
of the little ones of the poor of those who fear the future also listen to the cry
那些担心未来的人中的穷人中的一小部分也听着哭声
silent of our common home of the contaminated earth is sick there
那里没有我们污染土地的共同家园，在那里生病了
tenderness means using your hands and heart to caress each other for
温柔意味着用您的手和心脏互相爱抚
tenderness is the language of most people to take care of him
柔情是大多数人照顾他的语言
little ones of those who need the other a child becomes fond of and knows the father and
那些需要另一个孩子的孩子中的小孩子变得喜欢并认识父亲，
the mother for the caresses for the look for the voice for the tenderness
母亲为爱抚，为声音寻求温柔
I like to hear when dad or mom talk to their little baby
我喜欢听爸爸妈妈跟他们的小宝宝说话
when they too become children by speaking as the child speaks
当他们也随着孩子说话而成为孩子时
this is the tender age to lower oneself to the level of the other too
这也是使自己降低到另一个水平的温柔年龄
god lowered himself in jesus to rise to our level
上帝在耶稣里降低了自己，以提升到我们的水平
this is the road traveled by the good Samaritan
这就是好撒玛利亚人走过的路
this is the road traveled by jesus who is based who went through the whole
这是耶稣所走过的路，他走遍了整个路
life of man with a concrete language of love yes tenderness and
用爱的具体语言表达人的生活是温柔和
the path that the bravest and strongest men and women have traveled is not
最勇敢，最坚强的男人和女人走过的路不是
weakness the tenderness and strength and the road of solidarity the road
弱化温柔与力量，团结之路
of humility let me make it clear how much more powerful how much
谦卑让我弄清楚有多厉害有多少
the more your actions impact people the more you are called to be
您的行为对人的影响越多，您就被称为
humble because otherwise power will ruin you and you will ruin others
谦虚，因为否则力量会毁了你，你也会毁了其他人
in Argentina it was said that power is like the gene taken on an empty stomach
在阿根廷，有人说力量就像空着肚子的基因
who makes you dizzy makes you drunk makes you lose your balance and leads you to
谁让你晕眩使你醉酒使你失去平衡并导致你
hurt yourself and others if you don't combine it with humility e
如果不将其与谦卑相结合会伤害自己和他人
to tenderness with humility and concrete love instead the highest power is the
以谦卑和具体的爱来温柔，而最高的力量是
the stronger it becomes service and spreads the good, the future of humanity is not alone
它越能成为服务并传播利益，人类的未来就不再孤单
in the hands of the politicians of the great leaders of large companies
在大公司伟大领导人的政客手中
yes their huge responsibility but the future is above all in the hands
是的，他们承担着巨大的责任，但未来首先掌握在未来
of people who recognize each other as a tool and themselves as part of
互相承认是一种工具，而自己是其中一部分的人
a we need from each other and therefore please
我们彼此需要，因此请
remember me also with tenderness so that the task that was me may arise
也要温柔地记住我，这样我的任务就可能出现
entrusted for the sake of others of all of you of all of us
为了我们所有人中的其他人而受托
thank you [Applause]
谢谢[鼓掌]